# PAVAN K RAO

GAME DEVELOPER

# **PERSONAL PROFILE**

I am a passionate game programmer with 5 years of experience in developing games for mobile and PC in Unity. I am currently looking for opportunities to create impressive games and learn from some of the industry's seasoned veterans. Some of my favorite games are from the Castelvania, Darksouls, and DevilMayCry series.

## TECHNOLOGY SKILLS

# **CONTACT INFORMATION**

Phone: +91 7624853821 Email: raopavank@gmail.com

Address: BTM Layout, Bengaluru, Karnataka

560076, India

Portfolio: https://pavankrao-qlp.github.io/portfolio/

# **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

# **Associate Game Developer**

JumpStart Games | Bangalore (JAN 2018 - DEC 2019)

- Worked closely with art and design teams to develop features for Neopets: Legends and Letter.
- Worked on bug fixes and maintenance of various projects such as World Of Jumpstart, Math Blaster HyperBlast 2 HD, and Neopets: Ghoul Catchers.

# **Game Developer**

Moonfrog Labs. | Bangalore (JAN 2020 - Nov 2022)

- Ported the Ludo Club game from cocos2dx to Unity3D.
- Took part in live ops support and bug fixes for Ludo Club.
- Implemented several features such as achievements and collectibles on both the server(nodeJS) and the client-side(C#).
- Deployed and monitored server release on the production environment.
- Worked on adding functionality to admin tools and developer tools.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Bharathiar University**

B.Sc(Hons) in Game Development | 2014 - 2017

## **Mahesh PUC**

Intermediate (+2) 2012 - 2014

# PERSONAL PROJECTS

# **Lan Wars:** An online top-down multiplayer shooter (Unity)

- Implemented a peer-to-peer / server-client-based online multiplayer in Unity/C# using Unity Networking for PC.
- Handled adding animation and syncing it with character movements and actions.

# **Hide in Hide:** Single-tap-based rhythm game for Android.

 Developed the core mechanics of syncing enemy actions with thr BPM of background music in Unity.

## C++ Render Engine: C++ render engine using OpenGl

Developed a component based render engine in C++ and OpenGI
, supports loading of 3d models, blin-phong lighting, deferred
rendering and GUI,